Thomas Hubertz

Software Engineer

tjhubertz@gmail.com

Summary

Systems architect and developer with substantial experience in banking and insurance in addition to 10 years of Java programming experience. Familiar with Agile methods and Lean thinking.

I am currenlty working as an independent contractor and will be available january 2009

Specialties

Systems architecture, Software development in Java and Ruby, Payment integration, Systems analysis.

Experience

Consultant at Innoco AS

December 2008 - January 2009 (2 months)

Developed an application to support innovation in the organizations Innoco works with. The application was built with Ruby on Rails

Consultant at Protector Forsikring ASA

July 2008 - December 2008 (6 months)

Further development on the policy and invoicing system

Senior Developer at Protector Forsikring ASA

2004 - July 2008 (4 years)

System architect and lead programmer for the task of building the policy processing and invoicing system from scratch using

DB2,JBoss,J2EE,CMP,Struts,JSTL and XSLT.

- 2005, Interfacing core system to allow purchasing of life insurance via Skandiabanken.
- 2007, Enabling secure external access allowing brokers to produce policies directly into the system.
- 2008: Porting to Hibernate3

Co Founder and IT person at Mobilia AS

January 2003 - January 2008 (5 years 1 month)

Lead developer for building an sms/mms web application.

Invoved

- integration to sms/mms gateways
- integration to voice payment systems
- integration to credit card systems
- GUI implementation
- appserver configuration
- server configuration (backup etc)

JBoss, J2EE

Senior Developer at Skiinfo

2001 - 2004 (3 years)

- Developing YellowPages component for use with Skiinfo publishing system
- Developing solution for loading contactless access card before hitting the slopes. Involved online integration with credit card payment provider and skicard system.
- Functioning as technical reviewer in the work group choosing the payment solution for the 'innhodsnett' constallation which skiinfo was a part of.
- Working as a consultant for the company that was to be Protector Forsikring.

Oracle, Resin, J2EE, Struts, JSTL, XSLT, WebServices, Payment integration, Micro payment solutions

Vice President Research and Development at BBS

2000 - 2001 (1 year)

Resarch into new internet technology

Designing system architecture for next generation online banking services

Developing new services for the mobile internet

Developing new online banking services

Java & Corba

Adviser at BBS

1998 - 2000 (2 years)

Integrating with legacy data and logic residing on mainframe systems using Enterprise Java and CORBA technology

Extranet development

Evaluating Enterprise Java application servers and CORBA orbs.

Securing web applications using PKI

Senior Consultant at Posten SDS

1997 - 1998 (1 year)

Extending IBM's Etill to handle SET payments for remote internet shops using Java technology Designing and implementing internet shops
Researching micro-payment solutions

Systems Consultant at Accept Data

1996 - 1997 (1 year)

Developing client/server application for fund managers

Powerbuilder and Oracle

Education

The University of Edinburgh

MSc, Artificial Intelligence, 1995 - 1996

University of Newcastle-upon-Tyne

BSc, Software Engineering, 1992 - 1995

Activities and Societies: University Mens Basket Ball team coach and player

Thomas Hubertz

Software Engineer

tjhubertz@gmail.com



Contact Thomas on LinkedIn